<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Tim Trice</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Tim Trice</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Harvey Post Storm Report (Houston)</title>
      <link>/2017-09-06-hurricane-harvey-post-storm-report-houston/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017-09-06-hurricane-harvey-post-storm-report-houston/</guid>
      <description>library(dplyr) library(ggplot2) library(ggrepel) library(knitr) library(lubridate) library(plotly) library(purrr) library(rrricanes) library(stringr) library(tibble) library(tidyr) Per the National Weather Service in Houston, TX, the following data are preliminary results from Hurricane Harvey:
 THE DATA SHOWN HERE ARE PRELIMINARY….AND SUBJECT TO UPDATES AND CORRECTIONS AS APPROPRIATE.
  THIS REPORT INCLUDES EVENTS OCCURRING WHEN WATCHES AND/OR WARNINGS WERE IN EFFECT…OR WHEN SIGNIFICANT FLOODING ASSOCIATED WITH HARVEY OR ITS REMNANTS WAS AFFECTING THE AREA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Tornadic Tropical Cyclones</title>
      <link>/2017-08-26-top-tornadic-tropical-cyclones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017-08-26-top-tornadic-tropical-cyclones/</guid>
      <description>With Hurricane Harvey seemingly producing numerous tornadoes (many unconfirmed touchdowns) I wanted to get a view of the top tornadic-producing tropical cyclones.
History of tropical cyclone-spawned tornadoes lists the “Tropical cyclone tornado data set” (xls) as a source. However, this dataset does not include anything post-2015. I am unable to find an updated dataset.
As of this writing, officially Harvey has only produced two tornadoes. But, as a resident of the greater Houston area I can tell you the warnings are flying!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio in Docker</title>
      <link>/2017-05-17-rstudio-in-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017-05-17-rstudio-in-docker/</guid>
      <description>Brief Overview of Docker RStudio Server Pull rocker/rstudio from Docker Hub Pull rocker from GitHub Run r-base Build RStudio Image Run RStudio with R 3.4.0 Build and Run Rstudio with R 3.3.1 Commit Your Changes Conclusion   Docker is a container platform that helps replicate setups for testing and production from any system. It gives you the ability to set up a mini-operating system to meet specific criteria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Aggregation with R</title>
      <link>/r/r-basic-aggregation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/r/r-basic-aggregation/</guid>
      <description>Base Maximum Wind Minimum Pressure Count Cyclones per Year Average Wind Sample Standard Deviation Sample Variance  dplyr Maximum Wind Minimum Pressure Count Cyclones per Year Average Wind Sample Standard Deviation Sample Variance  data.table Maximum Wind Minimum Pressure Count Cyclones per Year Average Wind Sample Standard Deviation Sample Variance  Session Info   library(knitr) library(rrricanesdata) str(adv) ## Classes &amp;#39;tbl_df&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;tbl&amp;#39; and &amp;#39;data.frame&amp;#39;: 13036 obs. of 18 variables: ## $ Key : chr &amp;quot;EP062017&amp;quot; &amp;quot;EP062017&amp;quot; &amp;quot;EP062017&amp;quot; &amp;quot;EP062017&amp;quot; .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>