<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Tim Trice</title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Tim Trice</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>HURDAT 0.1.0</title>
      <link>/projects/hurdat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/hurdat/</guid>
      <description>Installation Included Datasets Atlantic (AL) Northeast Pacific (EP)  Variables Data Quality   HURDAT is a R package based off the Hurricane Re-Analysis Project by the Hurricane Research Division. The package contains two datasets; one for Atlantic Ocean cyclones and one for northeastern Pacific cyclones.
Installation HURDAT requires R version 3.4.0 or greater.
install.packages(&amp;quot;HURDAT&amp;quot;) library(HURDAT) # Additional libraries used for this document library(dplyr) library(ggplot2) library(Hmisc) library(knitr) library(purrr) library(readr)  Included Datasets The raw dataset is updated annually; typically during late winter or spring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>R HURDAT is a dataset from the Hurricane Re-Analysis project. It contains storm data for hundreds of cyclones for storms that have developed in the northwestern hemisphere (Atlantic and Pacific) since 1851.
rrricanes is a more comprehensive dataset of Atlantic and Pacific cyclones but only those since 1998. It gives access to as-issued text products for past and current cyclones including forecast and structure data.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rrricanes 0.1.0</title>
      <link>/projects/rrricanes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/rrricanes/</guid>
      <description>What is rrricanes Installing rrricanes About the Data Getting Data Basic Data Track Wind and Gust Pressure Seas  Wind Radius Hurricane Ike Wind Radius  Forecast Positions Forecast Wind Radius Future Plans Issues   To go along with my HURDAT package I’m releasing rrricanes, version 0.1.0. This library is not in cran and will not be submitted until release 0.2.0.
What is rrricanes I’ve had a fascination with hurricanes since I was a very little kid.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>