<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tim Trice</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tim Trice</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Harvey Post Storm Report</title>
      <link>/2017-09-06-hurricane-harvey-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017-09-06-hurricane-harvey-report/</guid>
      <description>Hurricane Harvey Barometric Pressure Wind Rain Tornadoes  Code Libraries Data  Previous Versions Session Info   On August 26, 2017, Hurricane Harvey made landfall along the central Texas gulf coast as a category four hurricane. The storm weakened but remained stationary in southeast Texas spawing dozens of tornadoes and dropping over 30 inches of rain in many locations with isolated amounts of over 50 inches.
Harvey was the first major hurricane to strike the Texas coast since Hurricane Rita in 2005; the first category four hurricane to make landfall since Hurricane Bret in 1999.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio in Docker</title>
      <link>/2017-05-17-rstudio-in-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017-05-17-rstudio-in-docker/</guid>
      <description>Brief Overview of Docker RStudio Server Pull rocker/rstudio from Docker Hub Pull rocker from GitHub Run r-base Build RStudio Image Run RStudio with R 3.4.0 Build and Run Rstudio with R 3.3.1 Commit Your Changes Conclusion   Docker is a container platform that helps replicate setups for testing and production from any system. It gives you the ability to set up a mini-operating system to meet specific criteria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing rrricanes, HURDAT</title>
      <link>/2017-05-16-introducing-rrricanes-hurdat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 10:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017-05-16-introducing-rrricanes-hurdat/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m proud to introduce two new packages for the R community: HURDAT and rrricanes.
Both packages are complimentary to one another.
HURDAT is a dataset of tropical cyclones that have developed in the Atlantic and northeast Pacific oceans since 1851 and 1949, respectively. HURDAT is a re-analysis project as conducated by the Hurricane Research Division of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration. They review known data to determine the best track, intensity and structure of a cyclone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I have a huge love of data and finding better solutions to known and unknown issues. For example, when I learned a team was manually entering information into their software, I developed a way to make it point-and-click saving several hours worth of work per week.
I began programming shortly after my son&amp;rsquo;s birth in 2003. I had already been somewhat exposed to MS Access when a company I worked for needed me to help clean their vendor data registers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Aggregation with MySQL</title>
      <link>/mysql/mysql-basic-aggregation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/mysql/mysql-basic-aggregation/</guid>
      <description>Maximum Wind Minimum Pressure Count Cyclones per Year Average Wind Standard Deviation Sample Standard Deviation Variance Sample Variance   Maximum Wind SELECT `Key`, MAX(`Wind`) AS MaxWind FROM `adv` GROUP BY `Key` ORDER BY `MaxWind` DESC LIMIT 0, 10;  Table 1: 10 records  Key MaxWind    EP202015 175  AL131998 155  EP202009 155  AL122005 150  AL182005 150  AL242005 150  EP142002 145  AL092004 145  AL042007 145  AL062007 145      Minimum Pressure SELECT `Key`, MIN(`Pressure`) AS MinPress FROM `adv` GROUP BY `Key` ORDER BY `MinPress` LIMIT 0, 10;  Table 2: 10 records  Key MinPress    EP202015 880  AL242005 882  AL182005 897  AL122005 902  AL131998 906  AL042007 906  EP202009 906  AL092004 910  EP142002 915  EP132014 918      Count Cyclones per Year SELECT YEAR(`Date`) AS `Yr`, COUNT(DISTINCT(`Key`)) AS `n` FROM `adv` GROUP BY YEAR(`Date`) ORDER BY `n` DESC LIMIT 0, 10;  Table 3: 10 records  Yr n    2005 46  2016 38  2000 37  2003 37  2012 36  2008 35  2015 34  2001 34  2010 33  2004 32      Average Wind SELECT `Key`, AVG(`Wind`) AS `AvgWind` FROM `adv` GROUP BY `Key` ORDER BY `AvgWind` DESC LIMIT 0, 10;  Table 4: 10 records  Key AvgWind    AL132003 102.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Aggregation with R</title>
      <link>/r/r-basic-aggregation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/r/r-basic-aggregation/</guid>
      <description>Base Maximum Wind Minimum Pressure Count Cyclones per Year Average Wind Sample Standard Deviation Sample Variance  dplyr Maximum Wind Minimum Pressure Count Cyclones per Year Average Wind Sample Standard Deviation Sample Variance  data.table Maximum Wind Minimum Pressure Count Cyclones per Year Average Wind Sample Standard Deviation Sample Variance  Session Info   library(knitr) library(rrricanesdata) str(adv) ## Classes &amp;#39;tbl_df&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;tbl&amp;#39; and &amp;#39;data.frame&amp;#39;: 13185 obs. of 18 variables: ## $ Key : chr &amp;quot;AL062017&amp;quot; &amp;quot;EP102017&amp;quot; &amp;quot;AL062017&amp;quot; &amp;quot;EP102017&amp;quot; .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description> R  HURDAT is a dataset from the Hurricane Re-Analysis project. It contains storm data for hundreds of cyclones for storms that have developed in the northwestern hemisphere (Atlantic and Pacific) since 1851.
 rrricanes is a more comprehensive dataset of Atlantic and Pacific cyclones but only those since 1998. It gives access to as-issued text products for past and current cyclones including forecast and structure data.
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>